Kate Braid fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Diaries, 1963-2012; F-10-19; 1.08 m of textual records
  - Diary, 1995; F-10-19-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary, 1996; F-10-19-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary, 2012; F-10-19-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary - travel diary - Europe, 1968; F-10-19-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-62)
  - Diary, 1987-1988; F-10-19-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-63)
  - Diary, 1988-1990; F-10-19-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-63)
  - Diary, 1990-1992; F-10-19-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-63)
  - Diary, 1992-1994; F-10-19-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-63)
  - Diary, 1994-1996; F-10-19-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-64)
  - Diary, 1996-1998; F-10-19-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-64)
  - Diary, 1999-2001; F-10-19-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-64)
  - Diary, 1998-2000; F-10-19-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-65)
  - Diary, 2000; F-10-19-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-65)
  - Diary, 2000-2001; F-10-19-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-65)
  - Diary, 2001-2002; F-10-19-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 10-65)
  - Diary, 2003; F-10-19-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 10-65)
  - Diary, 2003-2005; F-10-19-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 10-66)
  - Diary, 2005-2006; F-10-19-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 10-66)
  - Diary, 2006-2007; F-10-19-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 10-66)
  - Diary, 2006-2007; F-10-19-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 10-66)
  - Diaries - dream journals, 1989-2003; F-10-19-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 10-67)
  - Diary, 2007-2008; F-10-19-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 10-67)
  - Diary, 2008; F-10-19-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 10-67)
  - Diary, 2008-2010; F-10-19-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 10-67)
  - Diaries - notebooks, 1991-1996; F-10-19-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 10-68)
  - Diaries - notebooks, 1999-2010; F-10-19-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 10-68)
  - Diaries - notebooks, 1996-2001; F-10-19-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 10-68)
  - Diaries - travel diary - Germany, Czech Republic, France (1994) UK and Hungary (1998), 1994-1998; F-10-19-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 10-68)
  - Diaries - travel diary - Turkey Ukraine France, 2009; F-10-19-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 10-69)
  - Diary, 2010; F-10-19-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 10-69)
  - Diary, 2011; F-10-19-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 10-69)
  - Diary, 2011-2012; F-10-19-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 10-69)
  - Diaries - Notes and to-do lists, 1999; F-10-19-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
  - Diaries - Notes and to-do lists, 1999-2004; F-10-19-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 10-43)
  - Diaries - Quotations on notecards, 1990; F-10-19-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 10-55)
- First drafts and handwritten notes, 1976-2004; F-10-20; 12 cm of textual records
  Series consists of drafts of Braid's writing, primarily of her poetry.
  - Drafts, 1989-1998; F-10-20-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-70)
  - Drafts, 1995; F-10-20-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-70)
  - Drafts, 1985-1987; F-10-20-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-70)
  - Drafts, 1987-2002; F-10-20-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-70)
  - Drafts, 2000; F-10-20-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-71)
  - Drafts, 1976-2004; F-10-20-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-71)
- Sisters construction, 1963, 1985-1989; F-10-21; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of project notes, invoices, correspondence related to Braid's company Sisters Construction, which later became Sisters Productions.
  - Sisters construction - Graham project, 1985-1987; F-10-21-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
  - Sisters construction - Graham project, 1-985; F-10-21-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
  - Sisters productions, 1983-1985; F-10-21-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
  - Construction photographs plus 1 from 1963, 1963-1989; F-10-21-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-72)
- Publications, 1968-2012; F-10-22; 1.21 m of textual records
  Series consists of publications in which Braid's writing has appeared.
  - Pooka press, 2005; F-10-22-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-73)
  - Journeywoman (publication), 2012; F-10-22-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-73)
  - The house that Jill built (publication), 2005; F-10-22-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Literary review of Canada, 2006; F-10-22-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Labour studies in working class history of the americas, 2005; F-10-22-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Descant Cuba inside out, 2006; F-10-22-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - The Malahat review, 1990; F-10-22-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Room of one's own, 1990; F-10-22-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Canadian women's studies, 1981; F-10-22-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - The women's workbook, 1983; F-10-22-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 10-75)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Event, 1993; F-10-22-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - From awareness to action, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Arc, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Contemporary verse 2 (CV2), 2009; F-10-22-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - 2000% cracked wheat, F-10-22-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Taking action, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 10-76)
  - Emily Carr rebel artist - Japanese edition, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Homemaker's, 1980; F-10-22-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Event, 1993; F-10-22-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Families in transition, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Canadian dimension, 1988; F-10-22-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Hysteria, 1983; F-10-22-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1982; F-10-22-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - BC building tradesman, 1980; F-10-22-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Women in non-traditional occupations, 1979; F-10-22-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1980; F-10-22-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Speeches on women in trades, 1980; F-10-22-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Mayworks, 1988; F-10-22-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Because we are women, 1982; F-10-22-0-0-34 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - On the level, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-35 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - BC bookworld, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-36 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-37 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Herizons, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-38 (Archival box - standard 10-77)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1985; F-10-22-0-0-39 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Women in trades articles, 1979; F-10-22-0-0-40 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - The Canadian forum, 1996; F-10-22-0-0-41 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Posters for Covering rough ground readings, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-42 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - A journey of women ideas CBC, 1990; F-10-22-0-0-43 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Women in trades articles and poems, 1983; F-10-22-0-0-44 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Carpenter, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-45 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Our times, 2005; F-10-22-0-0-46 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Teacher, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-47 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - UTSA Here and now, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-48 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Women in trades articles and poems, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-49 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - The wilderness anthology, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-50 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Ecoforestry, 2001; F-10-22-0-0-51 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - This magazine, 1989; F-10-22-0-0-52 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Literary review of Canada, 2008; F-10-22-0-0-53 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Dandelion, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-54 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - ARC, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-55 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Our times, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-56 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Rhythm poetry magazine, 2008; F-10-22-0-0-57 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Chatelaine, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-58 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - A young tree, 1996; F-10-22-0-0-59 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - Ms. Magazine, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-60 (Archival box - standard 10-78)
  - From awareness to action strategies to stop sexual harrassment in the workplace, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-61 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The antigonish review, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-62 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Canadian bulletin of medical history, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-63 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The art tree, 2001; F-10-22-0-0-64 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Ms. Magazine, 1993; F-10-22-0-0-65 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The Canadian forum, 1997; F-10-22-0-0-66 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Women's education, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-67 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Our times, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-68 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The meliorist, 1997; F-10-22-0-0-69 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Saving trees, saving wildwood, 2001; F-10-22-0-0-70 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The wayward coast anthology, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-71 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Fireweed, 1993; F-10-22-0-0-72 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Pride and a paycheque, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-73 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Wordworks, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-74 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Saltwater, 1997; F-10-22-0-0-75 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - The word is out, 1997; F-10-22-0-0-76 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Poems of passion, poems of love, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-77 (Archival box - standard 10-79)
  - Matters of gender, 1996; F-10-22-0-0-78 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - The Malahat review, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-79 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Contemporary verse 2 (CV2), 2003; F-10-22-0-0-80 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Inward to the bones reviews and poems, 1998; F-10-22-0-0-81 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Event, 1997; F-10-22-0-0-82 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Canadian bulletin of medical history, 2003; F-10-22-0-0-83 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - The Malahat review, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-84 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Open letter, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-85 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Fireweed, 1996; F-10-22-0-0-86 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Love poems from Leaf press (3 volumes), 2003; F-10-22-0-0-87 (Archival box - standard 10-80)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1988; F-10-22-0-0-88 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-89 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1993; F-10-22-0-0-90 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Tradeswomen: a quarterly magazine, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-91 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - SFU labour program, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-92 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - This magazine, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-93 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Articles on Covering rough ground, 1995; F-10-22-0-0-94 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Fugue, 1996; F-10-22-0-0-95 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Canadian woman studies, 1994; F-10-22-0-0-96 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Left bank, 1992; F-10-22-0-0-97 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Labour studies journal, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-98 (Archival box - standard 10-81)
  - Room of one's own, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-99 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Contemporary verse 2 (CV2), 1991; F-10-22-0-0-100 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Fireweed, 1987; F-10-22-0-0-101 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Training the excluded for work, 2003; F-10-22-0-0-102 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1998; F-10-22-0-0-103 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - An exhibition of Canadian poetry, 2000; F-10-22-0-0-104 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - The edges of time, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-105 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - The Malahat review, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-106 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Atlantis, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-107 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - The capilano review, 1991; F-10-22-0-0-108 (Archival box - standard 10-82)
  - Larger than life, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-109 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Mosaic, 2002; F-10-22-0-0-110 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - CIL Oval, 1968; F-10-22-0-0-111 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Labour studies in working class history of the americas, 2011; F-10-22-0-0-112 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Canadian literature, 2010; F-10-22-0-0-113 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Various articles and newspaper clippings, 1998; F-10-22-0-0-114 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Precipice, 2009; F-10-22-0-0-115 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Hot sonnet, 2011; F-10-22-0-0-116 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Job stories, 1990; F-10-22-0-0-117 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - subTerrain, 2012; F-10-22-0-0-118 (Archival box - standard 10-83)
  - Canadian women's studies, 1981; F-10-22-0-0-119 (Archival box - standard 10-74)
  - Women who know wood: Kate Braid and Emily Carr, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-120 (Archival box - standard 10-74)
  - Our times, 1999; F-10-22-0-0-121 (Archival box - standard 10-74)
  - The antigonish review, 2010; F-10-22-0-0-122 (Archival box - standard 10-74)
  - Surfacing Columns for The Peak, 1974, 2015; F-10-22-0-0-123 (Archival box - standard 10-74)
- Covering rough ground, 1985-1998; F-10-23; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to Braid's writing and publication of Covering Rough Ground, her book of poetry about her early years in construction, which won the Pat Lowther Award for Best Book of Poetry by a Canadian Woman. Records include correspondence with publisher and readers, reviews, drafts, and poetry drafts.
  - Covering Rough Ground - correspondence with publisher and readers, reviews, readings, 1991-1998; F-10-23-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-42)
  - Covering Rough Ground - drafts, 1985-1991; F-10-23-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-42)
  - Covering Rough Ground - poetry drafts, 1985-1991; F-10-23-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-42)
- To this cedar fountain, 1990-2000; F-10-24; 6 cm of textual records
  Series includes records related to writing and publishing To this Cedar Fountain, Braid's book of poetry written in response to Emily Carr's paintings, which was nominated for the Dorothy Livesay (BC) Poetry Prize. Records include corresondence from readers, publisher, book reviews, interviews with Braid, and rough drafts.
  - To this Cedar Fountain - rough drafts, 1990-1995; F-10-24-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - To this Cedar Fountain -correspondence from readers, publisher, book reviews, interviews with Braid, 1992-2000; F-10-24-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 10-41)
  - To this Cedar Fountain (publication) - signed by Braid, 1995; F-10-24-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 10-41)